Guide to the Tomas Venclova Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, circa 1975-2003; Series VI
  - Copies of printed material signed by various authors, 1989-1995, undated (Box 25)
  - Copies of printed poems by Tomas Venclova, undated (Box 25)
  - Clippings, 1990s; 8 (Box 30)
  - Clippings, circa 1991-2004; 4 (Box 31)
  - Clippings, circa 1990-1996; 5 (Box 32)
- Electronic Files, 1997-2004; Series VII
  Conditions Governing Access
  Computer disks are restricted. Reference copies of electronic files are available. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - E-mail correspondence, drafts of writings, and photographs, 1997-2004; (1 computer disk)
    20041130-c.0001: Photos: Berlin 29.03.03 Oct 16, 04/Mails/Ms Word docs
  - E-mail correspondence, incoming and outgoing, circa 2000-2004
    20041130-c.0002
- Other Papers, 1976-2004; Series VIII
  - Address books, 2001-2004, undated; 3 (Box 26)
  - Travel receipts and tickets, 1990-2000, undated; 3 (Box 26)
  - Material related to Tomas Venclova's emigration, 1976-1990; 3 (Box 26)
  - Cards and other material for Tomas Venclova's 60th birthday, 1997; 3 (Box 26)
  - Ephemera related to Tomas Venclova's 60th birthday, 1997 (Box Roll 1)
  - Ephemera related to Tomas Venclova's 60th birthday, 1997 (Box Roll 2)
  - Passports and address books, 1985-1994, undated (Box 26)
  - Calendars, 1999-2002
  - Bibliographic cards, undated (Box 26)
  - Awards, 1978-2001; 3 (Box 26)
  - Honorary degrees, 1991-2000 (Box bsd)
  - Medals, 1978-1997, undated; 12 (Box 27)
  - Drawings of Tomas Venclova and his daughter Maria, undated
  - Caricature of various figures in Lithuanian culture by Andrius Cvirka (copy), 1999 (Box 29)
  - Souvenir pen, undated (Box 29)
- Oversize
  - Ephemera, announcements for Tomas Venclova's readings (Series III), 1976-2004, undated (Box 28)
  - Tomas Venclova with his daughter Maria and with N. Ogai (Series IV), circa 1975-1992 (Box 28)
  - Ne margi sakalėliai, by Virgilijus Noreika and Povilas Jaraminas (Series V), 1986; (1 phonographic disc) (Box 28)
  - Kūrybos vakaras, by Antanas Venclova (Series V), 1971; (1 phonographic disc) (Box 28)
  - Calendars (Series VII), 1999-2002 (Box 28)
  - Awards (Series VII), 1978-2001 (Box 28)
  - Drawings of Tomas Venclova and his daughter (Series VII), undated (Box 28)
- Restricted Material
  Box 33 (correspondence): Restricted until 2034 November 1. Box 34 (audiovisual materials): Restricted until 2054 September 24. Box 35 (diaries): Restricted until 2019 September 24. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Correspondence, 11 (Box 33)
  - Audio recordings of conversations with Joseph Brodsky, 1994; (3 audio cassettes) (Box 34)
  - Diaries, 1959-2003 (Box 35)
- Restricted Fragile
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Computer disk (20041130-c.0001) (Box 36)